(ﾆｰﾅ･ﾄﾞﾗﾝｺﾞ)たっだいま～！
(子供たち)ニーナ！
I'm home!
-Nina!
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)どうしても
神の国へ行きたいのです｡➡
I must go to the land of the gods.
何とぞ ご協力を｡➡
I implore your help.
もし ニーナが その者の
全ての顔を愛せるのなら➡
If you are able to embrace
those contradictions too,
その恋は 本物かもしれない｡
then your love may be real.
(母)大変だったね｡➡
It must have been hard.
あの子の懐き具合で分かるわ➡
I can tell from how attached she is.
あなたが
ニーナに優しくしてくれたこと｡
I can tell how kind you've been to her.
行ってくるね～！
I'm off, then!
So there are three tribes absent.
(魔族族長)現れぬ部族は ３つか｡
It has been five years since Cocytus fell.
(魔族族長)
コキュートスを失ってから５年｡➡
And we have been driven to this barren land.
Is there no hope for our future?
不毛の地へと追いやられた
我らの向かう先は➡
滅びしかないのか…｡
(魔族族長)たとえ➡
Even if I should perish,
この身が滅ぶとも
人間どもに思い知らせてやる｡
I will make the humans pay.
(ﾙｼﾌｪﾙ)
今 動いても しょうがないよ｡
Taking action now would accomplish nothing.
(ﾙｼﾌｪﾙ)人が使うあの力は
永遠ではない｡➡
The power the humans wield
is nothing permanent.
不釣り合いな力は
いずれ 滅びを招く｡➡
Power that is too great for its
master must wane,
１０年前の
ベルゼビュートのようにね｡
just as it did for Belzebuth ten years ago.
However, Lucifer,
(魔族族長)しかし ルシフェル様➡
I worry our continued survival may be difficult.
このまま生き長らえるのも
難しいかと｡
If we repeat the failings of the gods,
(ﾙｼﾌｪﾙ)神の二の舞になれば
それこそ滅びしかないよ｡
then that will indeed be our end.
(ﾙｼﾌｪﾙ)静観しよう｡
Let us watch and wait.
It will not be long
そう遠くないうちに
好機は必ず訪れるから｡
before the perfect opportunity
presents itself to us.
(魔族族長)
ルシフェル様のお考えに従おう｡
Let us follow Lucifer's lead.
あっ…｡
人にあらがう術を持たぬなら➡
If we lack the means to fight mankind,
then that is the wise choice.
それが賢明だ｡
Incidentally, Lucifer,
ところで ルシフェル様➡
have you discerned the whereabouts
of Azazel?
アザゼルの行方は
つかめましたか？➡
一人息巻いて
王都へと飛び出していったきり➡
There has been no word of him
since he stormed off to the human capital on his own.
音沙汰なく｡
もはや生きているのか…｡
I wonder if he is even still alive.
ザシュ！
(一同)わあ～！
グオォー グオォー！
次の挑戦者は アナティ史上➡
Our next challenger is
the deadliest killing machine
in Anatae's history!
最凶のキリングマシ～ン！➡
包帯悪魔～！
The Rag Demon!
こ… 殺せ｡
殺せ！
Kill him.
-Kill him!
-Kill him dead!
ぶっ殺せ！
死ね～！
Drop dead!
早く やっちまえ！
ぶっ殺せ！
Hurry up and kill him!
Kill him!
グルル…
Rage of Bahamut
They are the same
and lose themselves
Cuz there are lots of roads to go
And the path suddenly seems rougher
I wanna walk straight ahead
Knock down another dream
Most broke before they ever came true
But walk this way
Get out of my way
Depends on the way you think it
To a yielding heart
the future, hope,
despair and worry all look all the same
So much that you'll turn down the truth
that lied to you that day
when you were prepared for it all.
You go your way, don't you?
But walk this way
Get out of my way
バリバリッ！(雷鳴)
ザァーー(雨音)
≫バリバリッ！
(竜族族長の声)ダメだな こりゃ｡
えっ？
This isn't looking good.
(竜族族長の声)
前より 結界が強くなってて➡
The barrier is stronger than it was before.
I can't get any farther.
これ以上 進めねぇ｡
ええ～！
What?
(竜族族長の声)
お前たちだけで行くべ｡
You two will have to go on without me.
えっ 何それ！
What? What do you mean?
(竜族族長の声)うりゃあ～！
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ ﾆｰﾅ)いや～～！
Look, Nina!
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)ニーナ 見ろ！ ニーナ？
Nina?
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)入れ｡
Enter.
(ﾊﾝｻ)どうも～ 失礼します～｡
Hi there! Pardon us!
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)ん？
クワッ？➡
ムガロ？
Mugaro?
(ﾊﾝｻ ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)ん？
人との戦い以来 こんな感じだ｡
He has been this way
since our battle with the humans.
クワァ～！
だから 言ったじゃねぇか！
And I told you so, didn't I?
お前らのやり方じゃ
結局 従わねぇんだよ➡
No one's going to obey if you
do things your way.
あのガキも 人間もな｡
バッカス！
Not him and not the humans.
Bacchus!
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)
お前に エルの世話を任せたい｡
-I'd like to leave El's care to you.
-What now?
はあ？
やります｡ 神の仕事なら➡
Yes, of course! We would be happy to do
anything for you.
なんでもやりますクワァら｡
クワッ…｡
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)やなこった｡
なすりつけるんじゃねぇ！
No way!
Don't try to push this on me!
んんっ バッカス！
うるせぇ！➡
-Bacchus!
-Shut up!
I'm not babysitting a--
ガキの世話なんて…｡
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)従うのなら➡
If you do this,
酒を与えよう｡
えっ！
I shall reward you with wine.
Yes, I'll do it!
はい やります！
(ﾊﾝｻ)クワァ…｡
I leave it to you.
任せたぞ｡
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)はい！
Yes, ma'am!
エル君！
おじさんのこと 覚えてる？
El!
Do you remember me?
(ﾊﾝｻ)クワァ…｡
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)ん？ ん？➡
ふふふっ また よろしくね｡
Let's have fun again.
わあ～｡
It's huge! Jeanne!
でかっ！ ジャンヌさん！
あっ ジャンヌさん
クモ 嫌いだったもんね｡
Oh, that's right. You're scared of spiders.
神の国って こんななんだ｡
So this is what the land of the gods is like.
あっ！ ジャンヌさん
おいしそうな 木の実があるよ！
Oh, Jeanne!
There are some tasty looking berries!
わあ～ きれい！
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)おい 勝手に食べては…｡
You shouldn't eat them without--
They're so pretty! Time for a taste!
いっただっきま～す！
おい！
Hey!
うまぁ！ なんだ これ！
They're so good! What are these?
ジャンヌさんも食べてみ！
You should try one too, Jeanne!
確かに｡
でしょ！
You are right!
Right?
あっ かわいい天使さんだ｡
What a cute angel!
私たちに戦う気はない｡
We are not here to fight.
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)
私の名はジャンヌ･ダルク｡➡
My name is Jeanne D'Arc.
I came here riding on the back of an elder dragon
息子を捜して
竜の里の族長の背中に乗り➡
in search of my son.
この地へとやってきた｡
(ﾘﾄﾞ)本当に？
Is that true?
My son's name is El.
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)息子の名はエル｡
(天使たち)あっ…｡
If you know where he is, please share it with me.
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)居場所を知っていたら
教えてほしい｡
(ﾘﾄﾞ)あなたは？
And who are you?
What? Me?
えっ 私？ 私は… あっ➡
I'm....
私も お母さんです はい｡
I'm his mother too. Yes.
ダメですか…｡ すいません｡
No? Sorry.
私は
ジャンヌさんの友達です｡ ふふっ｡
I'm Jeanne's friend.
All of you, continue guarding the area.
(ﾘﾄﾞ)あなたたちは警備を続けて｡
(天使たち)はい｡
Yes, my lady.
(ﾘﾄﾞ)ついてきて｡
Follow me.
Is that a god's carriage?
(ﾘﾄﾞ)その馬車 神の？
バッカスって神様に借りてるの｡
(ﾘﾄﾞ)バッカス？➡
We're borrowing it from a god named Bacchus.
Bacchus?
知らない｡ 本当に神？
I have never heard of him.
Is he really a god?
(２人)たぶん｡
-Probably.
すてきな場所ね｡
What a beautiful place.
でも 想像してたより
ちょっと さみしい感じ｡
But it's a little more plain and empty
than what I imagined.
私 神の国って
もっとキラッキラだと思ってた｡
I thought the land of the gods would be
way more bright and sparkly.
There is something I would like to show you.
(ﾘﾄﾞ)見せたいものがある｡
Did I say something wrong?
何か
いけないこと言いました？ 私｡
わあ～ きれい！
見事だな｡
It's so pretty!
It is magnificent.
すごい すごい！
こんなの初めて！
Wow! I've never seen anything like this before!
≫(ﾘﾄﾞ)
この光は 消えていった神の記録｡
These lights represent the gods
who have fallen in battle.
(２人)えっ？
(ﾘﾄﾞ)少し前までは➡
Not long ago,
この国も活気に満ちてた｡
this kingdom was full of life.
But with Bahamut's return ten years ago,
でも
１０年前の バハムート復活で➡
多くの神が犠牲になった｡
many gods were lost.
The world was saved because of our sacrifice.
(ﾘﾄﾞ)そのおかげで
世界は救われたのに…｡
But instead of thanking us,
(ﾘﾄﾞ)あなたたち人間は
感謝するどころか➡
神を
世界から排除しようとした！➡
you humans tried to purge the gods
from existence!
Even in our recent battle,
この前の戦いでも➡
ここの光は いっぱい増えた｡
many more lights were added here.
この国に神が少ないのは
あなたたちのせいでもある！
The reason there are so few gods here
is partly your fault as well!
I am sorry.
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)すまない｡
Even the gods hate mankind.
(心の声)
≪人は 神様にも嫌われている≫
Is that what you really want?
≪本当に あなたは
そんなことを望んでいるの？≫
≪私には あなたの
考えていることが分からない≫
I just can't understand what you're thinking.
≪でも 嫌だ
あなたが みんなに嫌われるのは≫
I can't stand it.
I can't stand the idea of
≪嫌だ≫
everyone hating you.
(術者)うっ あぁ…｡
(術者)代われ｡
Switch with me.
冷却を急げ｡
Hurry up. Eibos' seal has reached its limit.
(ｼｬﾘｵｽ17世)
エイボスの封印は限界だ｡ 急げ｡
(考古学者)わしらも とうに
限界を超えておりますけどのう｡
We have long surpassed our limits as well.
(隊長)いつまで
もちますでしょうか？
How much longer do you think
it can hold?
今このとき 次元の狭間が開いても
おかしくない｡
A dimensional rift could open at any moment.
では その前に
封印を解かなくては｡
We must break the seal before then.
Perhaps we should leave this in heaven's hands.
運を天に任せてみますか｡
あっ｡ おっとっと…｡
My apologies.
When the time comes, the seal
will be broken,
時が来れば
エイボスの封印を解き➡
and I will have to fire this once again.
また こいつを撃つしかない｡
It is too dangerous.
(隊長)危険です｡
今 放てば 左目どころか…｡
You will lose more than your left eye
next time.
身を滅ぼそうとも
余は躊躇しない｡
Even if I should perish,
I will not hesitate.
お前たちも同じではないか？
Is it not the same for you?
It is better than the end of the world, isn't it?
世界が滅ぶよりは ましだろう｡
How long will your bodies be able to hold?
お前たちの体は いつまで もつ？
(隊長)そのときが来るまでは
必ず もたせます｡
We will be sure that they
hold until the right time.
Young men are always in a hurry to die.
(考古学者)若造どもは
すぐ死にたがる｡
Rage of Bahamut
Why am I trying to stay alive?
(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)
なぜ俺は 生きようとする…｡
Ta-da!
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)ジャジャ～ン！
は～い エル君 ご飯ですよ｡➡
Okay, El! It's time for dinner!
はい はい｡ ん？
Here you go.
いつまで すねてる気だ｡ ああ？➡
Just how long are you going to be pouting?
食え｡ 食わねぇと
お前のママに言いつけるぞ｡
Eat. If you don't eat, I'm going to tell your mother.
ほら 食え！ ほら｡
(ﾊﾝｻ)やめてくださいよ！➡
-Come on and eat!
-Please stop!
You shouldn't try to force this on poor Mugaro
when he's feeling so hurt.
傷ついてるムガロちゃんに
そんな無理強いして｡
Eat!
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)うう～！
(ﾊﾝｻ)クワッ！
We'll leave it right here.
ここに置いとくクワァら
食べたくなったら食べてね｡
If you get hungry, just help yourself.
必ず食えよ｡
(ｴﾙ)はっ…｡
You'd better eat.
(ﾊﾝｻ)クワァ～！
クワッ クワッ クワッ クワッ…｡
ああっ！
クワァ～！ クワッ？
(ｴﾙ)お母さん？
Mother.
You made it out safely.
無事だったのですね｡
Yes, thanks to you and your son.
ああ｡ お前たち親子のおかげでな｡
I'm so glad.
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)本当によかった｡
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)しかし➡
It's just....
In exchange, you two have....
それとは引き換えに
お前たち親子は…｡
Where is El?
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)エルは!? エルは どこに!?
Do not worry.
安心しろ ここにいる｡
He is here.
Thank goodness.
よかった｡
無事でよかった…｡
I'm glad he's okay.
It is good to see you, Jeanne.
≪(ｶﾞﾌﾞﾘｴﾙ)
よく来ましたね ジャンヌ｡
Gods are all so pretty.
神様って みんな きれいだね｡
Lady Gabriel,
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)ガブリエル様
エルに会わせてください｡
please allow me to see El.
(ｶﾞﾌﾞﾘｴﾙ)エルは今 軟禁しています｡
El is currently being confined.
はっ！ なぜですか？
Why?
(ｶﾞﾌﾞﾘｴﾙ)私は
エルの力を解放し 戦いに利用し➡
I unlocked El's powers
and used him for war,
人に敗れました｡
only to be defeated by mankind.
結果
彼の心は 我々から離れたのです｡
Because of this, his heart is no
longer with us.
ガブリエル様 エルは私の子｡
Lady Gabriel,
El is my child.
神のしもべであることは
変わりません｡
I am still a servant of the gods.
私に話をさせてください！
Please allow me to talk to him!
(ｶﾞﾌﾞﾘｴﾙ)ありがとう ジャンヌ｡
Thank you, Jeanne.
そうですね あなたなら
エルを導くことができましょう｡
Yes.
You might be able to lead El back to us.
What's wrong with the little brat?
どうしちまったんだ？ このガキ｡
さあ？
急に動クワァなくなっちゃって…｡
I don't know. He suddenly stopped moving.
(ﾊﾝｻ)不気味ですねぇ｡
It's a little creepy.
お母さん！
はい？
Mother!
エル！
El!
Mother!
お母さ～ん！➡
お母さん｡
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)エル！
-Mother!
-El!
(ｴﾙ)お母さん｡
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)エル｡
-Mother!
-El!
Mother!
(ｴﾙ)お母さん…｡
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)エル…｡
≪うぅ…｡
(ﾊﾝｻ)クワァ～！
Nina!
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)ニーナ！
(ﾊﾝｻ)お嬢さん！
うぅ… あんたたちもいたの？
You guys were here too?
Yeah! We were!
いたの いたの｡
うわぁ～ん よかったよ～！
I'm so happy!
よし！ よし来い！ ニーナ‼
Come here!
Nina!
えっ!?
ジャンヌさん！
Jeanne!
よがっだ！ ああ～ よがっだよ！
Thank goodness! I'm so happy!
(２人)そっちかよ！
-What about us?
(ｴﾙ)お母さんと別れたあと
僕は 人に見つかることなく➡
After I was separated from you,
I was able to hide among the demon slaves
悪魔の奴隷に紛れ込めた｡
without being found by the humans.
(ｴﾙ)喉を焼かれて
売りに出されたんだ｡
My throat was branded,
and I was sold off.
(ｴﾙ)((あっ… ううっ…))
(奴隷商人)((ふふっ))
((ううっ… うっ…))
(奴隷商人)((ははっ))
((≫バリバリッ！))
((ふふふっ))
(奴隷商人たち)
((うわっ！ ああっ！))
((ドドォーン！(雷鳴)))
I did just as you told me to
(ｴﾙ)
僕は お母さんに言われたとおり➡
最初に助けてくれた人に
なんとか ついていった｡
and followed the first person who helped me.
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)アザゼルか｡
お母さん 知り合いなの？
That was Azazel?
You know him?
昔 少しな｡
I used to a long time ago.
あの人は すごいんだよ｡
たった一人で➡
He's amazing!
He went out all alone to fight
for the poor demons.
かわいそうな悪魔のために
戦い続けて｡
本当は正しい人なんだ｡
あっ…｡
He's actually a good person.
Mother, please let me out of here.
お母さん ここから僕を出して｡
えっ！
Leave to do what?
出てどうする？
下界へ行く｡
I will go back to the surface world.
危険だ｡
(ｴﾙ)お母さんは取り戻せた｡
It is too dangerous.
I was able to get you back.
次の 僕の使命は
世界を平和にすることなんだ｡
Now my next duty
is to bring peace to the world.
You know what is happening, don't you?
お母さんだって
知ってるでしょ？➡
下界に はびこる悪意を…
誰かが正さなきゃいけない｡
Someone must right the evils
spreading throughout the world.
And I have the power to do so.
そして 僕には その力がある｡
≪(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)おごるな エル｡
あっ｡
Watch your arrogance, El.
You cannot fulfill your duty in your current state.
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)
今のお前では 使命を果たせない｡
Then why did you make me fight?
じゃあ なんで僕に戦わせたの？
戦争をさせたの？
Why did you send me to war?
ここから出せ｡
Let me out of here.
The answer remains the same.
何度言っても同じことだ｡
ガブリエル様の…｡
Lady Gabriel--
Listening to Gabriel will get you nowhere.
(ｴﾙ)ガブリエルの言うことなんて
聞いてもダメだよ｡
(ｴﾙ)
ガブリエルに世界は救えない｡➡
Gabriel cannot save the world.
救えるのは➡
The only one who can save it...
僕だ｡
is me.
As horrible as you are
I can't help but love you
Even while I waited
That is all I felt
Ephemeral lovers, both flawed and missing pieces
We have finally become one
in this miniature garden at the edge of sorrow
Can you hear my heart speaking?
Ah, I may no longer feel
that I want to go back in time
But there are feelings, feelings, feelings
I can only feel now
I want to run away with you, dancing
just like in a fairy tale
Don't tell me it will only be this once, darling
I am on the same ark
Sha-ra-ran-la, Sha-ra-ran-la
Yeah
Cinderella step
Sha-ra-ran-la, Sha-ra-ran-la
Yeah
Cinderella step
-It's Lucifer.
-This is Azazel.
-We're the Fallen Angel Brothers.
You seem extremely happy to be
surrounded by so many books.
Next time on Rage of Bahamut:
Virgin Soul, "City of the Gods, Part 2"
I'm very happy right now.
BAHA SOUL!!
Baha Baha Baha Soul.
I want you...
to watch next time too.